Register of the Milton Friedman papers 77011.4088897
Hoover Institution Archives
- Incremental Sound Recordings, 1966-1999 (Boxes 234-236)
  - Milton Friedman Speaks, 1977-1978; 35.0 sound cassettes
    - "The Economics of Medical Care," lecture delivered at the Mayo Foundation, Rochester, Minnesota, 1978 May 19; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 235)
      "The major reason for the rise in the cost per day of hospital care is not a rise in prices in excess of inflation--not at all. The major reason is an increase in the number, variety, and complexity of the procedures that are being used, tests that are being made, services that are being rendered to the American citizen."
  - "The Future of Our Free Society: A Conversation with Milton Friedman,", 1978 February 21; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 235)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007240
    Conducted at the American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research "Conversation Series."
  - Philadelphia Society - 30th National Saturday Luncheon, 1994 April 23; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007490
    Milton Friedman addresses the Philadelphia Society on the occasion of its 30th anniversary. He comments on the progress of its ideals over the time. He says they have won in the realm of ideals but lost in the realm of policy. After this, officers of the society and others comment on the work of the society.
  - Milton Friedman interview by John Callaway on Nightline, WBBM Radio, 1966 January 30; 90.0 minutes (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007516
    This is the portion of the interview conducted between 8:30 and the ten o'clock news. The second segment, with listeners' comments and questions, was on a second tape which WBBM has apparently not been able to locate. This tape is not broadcast quality; it was intended for transcription use only.
  - "Nixon's New Controls: A TeleSession with 12 Leading Economists,", circa 1971; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007489
    Over a telephone conference call, various economists weigh in on domestic and international economic policy.
  - "A Simple Idea Whose Time Has Come: Tax Limitation," interview for the Manion Forum broadcast, 1973 October 28; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007493
    Milton Friedman speaks about tax limitation, particularly a proposition on California's ballot.
  - "An Economic Perspective,", 1975 February 7; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007494
    This was Wall Street Week television program number 428, with host Louis Rukeyser and special guest Friedman.
  - "Friedman on the Election,", 1976 November 5; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007495
    This was Wall Street Week television program number 619, with host Louis Rukeyser and special guest Friedman.
  - "Supply-Side Policies: Where Do We Go From Here?,", 1982 March 17-18; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007497
    This Friedman lecture about supply-side economics in the 1980s was recorded in Atlanta, Georgia.
  - Milton Friedman speech in Berkeley, 1985 April 24; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007498
    Friedman speaks about the poor, unemployment, and antipoverty government programs. Friedman's remarks are complete on this audio cassette, but the remarks of others who spoke after him are not complete.
  - "Free Market and Free Speech,", 1986 March 7; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007499
    This was Friedman's keynote address delivered at the Federalist Society Nationalist Symposium on March 7, 1986, at the Stanford University Law School. The recording also contains some of the proceedings leading up to the keynote address.
  - "Portfolio of State Issues" (volume 4, number 2), circa 1987; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007500
    Friedman and William F. Buckley Jr. speak about the tax cuts and economic policy of the Reagan administration.
  - "In Defense of Dumping," Commonwealth Club of California, 1987 July 17; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Scope and Content note
    This item has been digitized as part of the Commonwealth Club of California records. Listen to the recording at: http://miltonfriedman.hoover.org/objects/1847
  - "Free Markets and Free Men," lecture delivered at the Chinese University of Hong Kong, 1988 September 27; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007503
    Friedman speaks about the intersection of free markets and free societies.
  - Milton Friedman describing his trip to China, 1988 September 27; 2.0 sound cassettes (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007502
  - "Communism and Markets," Commonwealth Club of California, 1989 July 21; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    This item has been digitized as part of the Commonwealth Club of California records. Listen to the recording at: http://miltonfriedman.hoover.org/objects/2059
  - Recording of freedom and technology dinner, 1989 November 16; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007505
    This dinner was co-sponsored by the Cato Institute and Pacific Research Institute. The featured speakers are George Gilder and Milton Friedman.
  - Milton Friedman describing his 1990 European trip, circa 1990; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007507
  - "Prospects for the Nineties: Reaganomics in Reverse?," speech at the National Financial Advisor Conference, Charles Schwab and Company, Inc., 1991; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007508
  - "Why Government Is the Problem," Visions of Liberty (1992 Laissez Faire Books, San Francisco, California), 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007510
    David Boaz interviews Milton Friedman, followed by a general discussion with other economists as well.
  - Speech at the luncheon session of the Educational Choice Conference sponsored by the Pacific Research Institute, San Francisco, 1992 May 1; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007509
  - Milton Friedman describing his trip to China, 1993 October; 2.0 sound cassettes (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007515
    Milton Friedman gives a detailed recounting, nearly hour-by-hour, of the trip he and his wife made to China in October 1993. He remarks on the places he went; people he met; and observations he made about the country, its people, and culture.
  - Friedman on "Bridges: A Liberal/Conservative Dialogue" with Larry Josephson, circa 1996; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007517
  - "Issues in Education,", 1997 May 17-24; 1.0 sound cassette (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007518
    Part 1: "Vouching for Vouchers" by Milton Friedman, 17 May 1997. Part 2: "The New Absolutes" by Bill Watkins, 24 May 1997.
  - "How to Cure Medical Care," Richard J. Bartlett M.D. Memorial Lecture for The Saint Francis Foundation, San Francisco, 1999 November 4; 1.0 sound cassettes (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 77011_a_0007519